================================================
       Plugin of the Month, February 2010
Brought to you by the Autodesk Developer Network
================================================
----------
Screenshot
----------

Description
----------
This plugin can be used with Inventor to simplify the process of
capturing images of parts of documents, or the entire document
or application windows. It optionally allows you to remap the
background to white and the foreground to black, and convert the
entire image to grayscale, as well as sending the capture image
directly to a printer.

System Requirements
-------------------
This plugin has been tested with Inventor 2008 onwards.

An installer package which should work for both 32- and 64-bit
systems is provided.

The source code has been provided as a Visual Studio 2008 project
containing VB.NET code (not required to run the plugin).

Installation
------------
Run the InventorScreenshot.msi installer.

Building the source-code in Visual Studio should also cause the
plugin to be registered, as long as the application has been
"enabled for COM Interop" via the project settings.

Usage
-----
Once loaded, an additional panel containing the Screenshot command
should be available in the Part, Assembly, Drawing, Presentation
or Tools Ribbon. If your version of Inventor is not using the
Ribbon interface, you should find a menu item under the Tools
menu.
 
When you run the Screenshot command, a dialog will appear. This
dialog provides you with the Selection Options and Settings. It also
displays a preview of the screenshot.

The snapshot will be taken according to the Selection Options and
converted to a final bitmap according to the Settings.

You have options to save the bitmap to the clipboard to a file or
send it directly to a printer.

When choosing the "Application" or "Document" option, the limits of
the screenshot will be calculated automatically. When using the
"Window" option, the user needs to select a region of the screen.

Selection Options
  |_Document:    capture the active Inventor document window
  |_Application: capture the entire Inventor application window
  |_Window:      select a region to capture using "Window<"

Settings:
	|_Background
	|	|_Normal:    the current background color is used
	|	|_White:     the background is forced to white	
	|_Foreground
	|	|_Normal:    the current background color is used
	|	|_Black:     the foreground is forced to white 	 	
	|_Grayscale
		|_Off:       do not convert the image to grayscale
		|_On:        convert the entire image to grayscale

The settings for each option are maintained to allow quick capture
of common images.

When settings are changed that require the bitmap to be re-generated
a progress dialog will be displayed.

The output location causes the resultant image to be placed on the
clipboard, saved to a file or sent to the printer.

"Save Screenshot" will cause the image to be saved to the selected
output location(s).

"Exit" will cause the dialog to close.

Uninstallation
--------------
You can unload the plugin without installing it by unchecking the
"Load" checkbox associated with the plugin in the Inventor Add-In
Manager.

Unchecking "Load on Startup" cause the plugin not to be loaded in
future sessions of Inventor.

To remove the plugin completely, uninstall the application via
your system's Control Panel.

Known Issues
------------
The tool simply captures the graphics via the screen's display buffer:
if unwanted application windows are obscuring the image, in some way,
then this may need additional handling.

The tool will also capture Inventor's navigation aids, such as the
ViewCube. These can be turned off manually via the Application
Settings, if needed, but are not currently hidden automatically by
the plugin.

If graphics from the Screenshot dialog are included in the capture,
it's possible to adjust the delay used by the tool to avoid such
a situation. Open the app.config file installed with the plugin
into a text editor and adjust the delayTime setting, as appropriate
(the default value is 500ms).

Author 
------
This plugin was written by Xiaodong Liang, based on a plugin for
AutoCAD developed by Kean Walmsley.

Acknowledgements
----------------
Many thanks to Alex Fielder and Fenton Webb for their input during
the design and testing of this plugin.

Further Reading
---------------
For more information on developing with Inventor, please visit the
Inventor Developer Center at http://www.autodesk.com/developinventor 

Feedback
--------
Email us at labs.plugins@autodesk.com with feedback or requests for
enhancements.

Release History
---------------

1.0    Original release
1.1    Added support for Inventor 2008 and 2009
1.1.1  Fixed the problem of selecting a region in perspective view
       Fixed the problem of printing on a 64-bit OS

(C) Copyright 2010 by Autodesk, Inc. 

Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software in 
object code form for any purpose and without fee is hereby granted, 
provided that the above copyright notice appears in all copies and 
that both that copyright notice and the limited warranty and restricted 
rights notice below appear in all supporting  documentation.

AUTODESK PROVIDES THIS PROGRAM "AS IS" AND WITH ALL FAULTS.  
AUTODESK SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY IMPLIED WARRANTY OF MERCHANTABILITY OR 
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE.  AUTODESK, INC.  DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE 
OPERATION OF THE PROGRAM WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR FREE.